Have you got any gadgets hanging around your home that you no longer want or use?
你家里是不是堆着一些不再想要或使用的小电子产品？
Between us, we have millions of bits of tech stockpiled in drawers that could be given a new lease of life.
我们所有人的抽屉里，总共囤积着数百万件这类科技产品，而它们其实完全可以重获新生。
Part of the problem for our unloved gadgets is that many become obsolete quickly because their software doesn’t get updated.
这些被我们闲置的电子产品之所以会被淘汰，部分原因是它们的软件无法更新，导致很快就过时了。
Other items are left unused because they’re broken or they’ve become superseded by a fancy new version.
还有一些则是因为损坏，或是被更精致的新款产品取代而被束之高阁。
Many of these items are electronics, but despite them appearing to be past their sell-by date, they don’t need to end up in landfill.
这些物品大多都属于电子产品，虽然看似已经毫无用处，但它们其实并不需要被扔进垃圾填埋场。
There are several ways to make the most of our unwanted gadgets.
想要充分利用这些闲置电子产品，其实有好几种方法。
Recycling is the obvious solution.
回收利用是最显而易见的一种。
Materials used to make them can be extracted and reused in other things.
制造这些产品的原材料可以被提取出来，再用于其他物品的生产。
As an example, Elisabeth Ratcliffe from the Royal Society of Chemistry told the BBC: “There are about thirty different elements just in a smartphone, and many of them are very rare.”
英国皇家化学会的伊丽莎白·拉特克利夫在接受BBC采访时举例说：“一部智能手机里就含有大约30种不同的元素，其中很多都是稀有元素。”
These can be used in touch screens and solar panels.
这些元素可以用于制造触摸屏和太阳能电池板。
Probably the best antidote to our throwaway culture is to repair our broken tech.
想要应对我们当下的“用完即弃”文化，最好的办法或许就是修理损坏的电子产品。
This takes patience and skill, which can be learnt at repair clubs and repair cafés – free meeting places where you’ll find tools and materials to help you make any repairs you need.
这需要耐心和技巧，而这些都可以在修理俱乐部和修理咖啡馆里学到——这些免费的聚会场所会提供工具和材料，帮你完成所需的各类修理工作。
In the UK, the interest in mending our stuff and giving it a new life is reflected by the popularity of a TV series called The Repair Shop, where craftspeople rescue and resurrect items their owners thought were beyond saving.
在英国，一档名为《修复店》的电视节目大受欢迎，这一现象也反映出人们对于修理物品、赋予其新生的浓厚兴趣。节目里的手工艺人会拯救并修复那些被主人认为已经无法挽救的物品。
A final option for your discarded gadgets is to upcycle them.
处理废旧电子产品的最后一种办法是升级改造。
You can breathe new life into unwanted stuff by transforming it into valuable pieces or collectable retro items.
你可以将这些闲置物品改造成有价值的物件或是具有收藏价值的复古单品，让它们重焕生机。
These could be sold on, meaning you can make some cash from your junk and create much needed space in your home!
这些改造后的物品还可以拿去出售，这样你既能用“废品”赚点钱，又能为家里腾出急需的空间！